[
  {
    "question": "The technician ______ already _____ the new circuit.",
    "options": ["has installed", "have installed", "installed", "is installing"],
    "answer": "has installed"
  },
  {
    "question": "I can’t _______ my tools. Have you seen them?",
    "options": ["find", "finding", "found", "finds"],
    "answer": "find"
  },
  {
    "question": "We can’t work without our safety ________.",
    "options": ["gloves", "glove", "gloving", "glove’s"],
    "answer": "gloves"
  },
  {
    "question": "The workers _______ the machine yesterday.",
    "options": ["repair", "repaired", "repairing", "repairs"],
    "answer": "repaired"
  },
  {
    "question": "I _______ an email to my client last night.",
    "options": ["send", "sending", "sent", "sends"],
    "answer": "sent"
  },
  {
    "question": "We will _______ the meeting at 9 a.m.",
    "options": ["start", "started", "starts", "starting"],
    "answer": "start"
  },
  {
    "question": "The programmer ________ a new app for  the company comercial brand.",
    "options": ["created", "creates", "creating", "create"],
    "answer": "created"
  },
  {
    "question": "They happily _________ the documents before the deadline.",
    "options": ["finishing", "finishes", "finish", "finished"],
    "answer": "finished"
  },
  {
    "question": "A. Did you ______ the invoice to the supplier?\nB. Yes, I did it an hour ago.",
    "options": ["send", "sent", "sends", "sending"],
    "answer": "send"
  },
  {
    "question": "You’re in a technical workshop. The instructor says: “Plug in the cable.” You should:",
    "options": ["Connect it to the socket", "Remove it", "Cut it", "Paint it"],
    "answer": "Connect it to the socket"
  },
  {
    "question": "The electrician ________ the cables incorrectly. He needed to read the manual gently.",
    "options": ["connect", "connecting", "connected", "connects"],
    "answer": "connected"
  },
  {
    "question": "We _______not _______ the production materials on time.",
    "options": ["did / receive", "did / received", "do / received", "didn’t / received"],
    "answer": "did / receive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where ______ you ________ your internship?",
    "options": ["did / do", "do / did", "have / done", "are / doing"],
    "answer": "did / do"
  },
  {
    "question": "They _______ all the machines before the external inspection.",
    "options": ["check", "checked", "checking", "checks"],
    "answer": "checked"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accountant ________ come to work last week.",
    "options": ["did", "didn’t", "wasn’t", "don’t"],
    "answer": "didn’t"
  },
  {
    "question": "The students _________ the online test successfully.",
    "options": ["complete", "completed", "completes", "completing"],
    "answer": "completed"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accounting, a ledger is ___.",
    "options": ["a person who pays taxes", "a book or file that records financial transactions", "a receipt", "a bank account"],
    "answer": "a book or file that records financial transactions"
  },
  {
    "question": "A server is used to ___.",
    "options": ["prepare coffee", "manage network data and resources", "store printed files", "fix electrical cables"],
    "answer": "manage network data and resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "A mechanical drawing shows __________ .",
    "options": ["a list of materials", "the design of a part or machine", "only colors and shapes", "a figure of a house"],
    "answer": "the design of a part or machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accountant __________ the financial reports every month.",
    "options": ["prepare", "prepares", "preparing", "prepared"],
    "answer": "prepares"
  },
  {
    "question": "A. Are you _________to install the new software today?\nB. Yes, I am.",
    "options": ["going", "go", "will", "did"],
    "answer": "going"
  },
  {
    "question": "I think technology _________ change more and more the job market trend.",
    "options": ["was", "is", "will", "has"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "question": "I ________not attend the meeting because I’m sick.",
    "options": ["will", "am going to", "did", "have"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "question": "He _________ probably arrive late to the office. He is having a parking problem.",
    "options": ["will", "has", "did", "are"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "question": "The mechanic ________ test the components for the engine tomorrow.",
    "options": ["is going to", "will", "was", "have"],
    "answer": "is going to"
  },
  {
    "question": "The motor ___ automatically when the power is off.",
    "options": ["stops", "stop", "stopped", "stopping"],
    "answer": "stops"
  },
  {
    "question": "She ___ in the Human Resources department.",
    "options": ["work", "works", "working", "worked"],
    "answer": "works"
  },
  {
    "question": "The new student _________ English twice a week.",
    "options": ["study", "studies", "studied", "studying"],
    "answer": "studies"
  },
  {
    "question": "My family __________ to church every Sunday morning.",
    "options": ["go", "went", "is going", "goes"],
    "answer": "goes"
  },
  {
    "question": "They ________ not using these machines anymore.",
    "options": ["aren’t", "do", "didn’t", "are"],
    "answer": "are"
  },
  {
    "question": "A “circuit breaker” is used to:",
    "options": ["turn on computers", "stop electrical current in emergencies", "control network access", "reduce voltage automatically"],
    "answer": "stop electrical current in emergencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "“Inventory control” means:",
    "options": ["managing materials and products in stock", "organizing workers’ schedules", "sending emails to clients", "repairing machines"],
    "answer": "managing materials and products in stock"
  },
  {
    "question": "In programming, a “bug” is:",
    "options": ["a system error", "a new software", "a database", "an input device"],
    "answer": "a system error"
  },
  {
    "question": "The “human resources department” deals with:",
    "options": ["employee management", "financial auditing", "logistics", "product sales"],
    "answer": "employee management"
  },
  {
    "question": "In mechatronics, “sensor” means:",
    "options": ["a device that detects physical changes", "a power generator", "an electric motor", "a resistor"],
    "answer": "a device that detects physical changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cable is ________ the wall and the table.",
    "options": ["between", "under", "behind", "in"],
    "answer": "between"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bank documents are ________ the drawer.",
    "options": ["in", "on", "at", "behind"],
    "answer": "in"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IT Department __________efficiently the new network.",
    "options": ["installed", "installs", "installing", "install"],
    "answer": "installed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The company ________ a new and successful branch in Arequipa, Peru.",
    "options": ["open", "opened", "opening", "openning"],
    "answer": "opened"
  },
  {
    "question": "I _________ my password yesterday, so I had to create a new one.",
    "options": ["forgot", "forget", "forgetting", "forgets"],
    "answer": "forgot"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator _________ the wrong button. He caused an alarm attention in the street.",
    "options": ["push", "pushed", "pushing", "pushes"],
    "answer": "pushed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The machines __________ automatically.",
    "options": ["work", "works", "working", "worked"],
    "answer": "work"
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you _________ in the Human Resources office?",
    "options": ["works", "working", "work", "worked"],
    "answer": "work"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engineer ________ not design websites.\nShe gives technical support to hardware problems.",
    "options": ["does", "do", "is", "did"],
    "answer": "does"
  },
  {
    "question": "My teacher always ________ to class on time.",
    "options": ["come", "comes", "coming", "came"],
    "answer": "comes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The secretary ________ the phone calls in the morning.",
    "options": ["answers", "answer", "answering", "answered"],
    "answer": "answers"
  },
  {
    "question": "We _________ in the testing laboratory twice a week.",
    "options": ["work", "works", "worked", "working"],
    "answer": "work"
  },
  {
    "question": "A. Where _________ you live?\nB. I live in a house in the suburbs",
    "options": ["does", "do", "are", "did"],
    "answer": "do"
  },
  {
    "question": "In IT, “software” refers to:",
    "options": ["physical parts of a computer", "mechanical devices", "computer programs", "electrical tools"],
    "answer": "computer programs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the software ________any errors?",
    "options": ["have", "has", "having", "had"],
    "answer": "have"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accountant __________ carefully  the balance at the end of every month.",
    "options": ["check", "checks", "checked", "checking"],
    "answer": "checks"
  },
  {
    "question": "There isn’t ________ paper left in the printer.",
    "options": ["any", "some", "a", "few"],
    "answer": "any"
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you have __________ pen?",
    "options": ["a", "much", "any", "some"],
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "I need ________ information about the new project in the company.",
    "options": ["any", "some", "many", "few"],
    "answer": "some"
  },
  {
    "question": "In business, “supplier” means:",
    "options": ["a person or company that provides goods", "a worker", "a manager", "a consumer"],
    "answer": "a person or company that provides goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "A “client” is generally:",
    "options": ["the person who buys services or products", "the person who sells items", "the person who offers goods and services", "the designer"],
    "answer": "the person who buys services or products"
  },
  {
    "question": "In IT, a “backup” is always:",
    "options": ["a copy of data for protection", "a hardware failure", "a system update", "a technical report"],
    "answer": "a copy of data for protection"
  },
  {
    "question": "The “production line” is:",
    "options": ["a process where goods are manufactured", "a telephone line", "a design team", "an accounting system"],
    "answer": "a process where goods are manufactured"
  },
  {
    "question": "A “Industrial technician” is a person who usually:",
    "options": ["repairs or operates technical systems", "writes reports", "manages accounts", "sells products"],
    "answer": "repairs or operates technical systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "In electricity, a “fuse” protects:",
    "options": ["circuits from overcurrent", "cables from dust", "software from viruses", "batteries from heat"],
    "answer": "circuits from overcurrent"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main goal of “preventive maintenance” is:",
    "options": ["to avoid machine failures", "to repair broken parts", "to reduce worker hours", "to increase bills"],
    "answer": "to avoid machine failures"
  },
  {
    "question": "In marketing, a “target market” means:",
    "options": ["the group of consumers a company wants to reach", "the product design team", "the competitors", "the sales department"],
    "answer": "the group of consumers a company wants to reach"
  },
  {
    "question": "A “database” is also called:",
    "options": ["a collection of organized information", "a type of cable", "a financial program", "a device for sound"],
    "answer": "a collection of organized information"
  },
  {
    "question": "“Entrepreneurship” means:",
    "options": ["creating and managing new businesses", "studying accounting", "repairing machines", "managing salaries"],
    "answer": "creating and managing new businesses"
  },
  {
    "question": "I promise I _______ send the email soon.",
    "options": ["will", "am going", "did", "was"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IT team _______ upgrade all systems this weekend.",
    "options": ["will", "are going to", "were", "was"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "question": "Our boss ______ evaluate our performance next Friday.",
    "options": ["will", "was", "have", "did"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “AC” stand for in electricity ?",
    "options": ["Automatic Circuit", "Alternating Current", "Active Control", "Applied Conductor"],
    "answer": "Alternating Current"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading Question. Every morning, the maintenance team _________all the electrical panels in the main factory building. They look for signs of overheating and loose connections. If any problem is found, the technician immediately disconnects the system and replaces the damaged part.",
    "options": ["controls", "checks", "organizes", "looks at"],
    "answer": "checks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading Question. In the administration department, all resources are carefully managed to avoid waste. The office manager controls the purchase of materials such as paper, ink, and computer accessories. Before any order is approved, the manager compares prices from at least three __________",
    "options": ["suppliers", "customers", "retailers", "promoters"],
    "answer": "suppliers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Would you like ________ some coffee?",
    "options": ["having", "to have", "have", "had"],
    "answer": "to have"
  },
  {
    "question": "I would ________ to visit The Great Wall of China someday.",
    "options": ["like", "liking", "likes", "liked"],
    "answer": "like"
  },
  {
    "question": "What would you do if the system failed?",
    "options": ["I reset it.", "I will reset it.", "I would reset it.", "I reset it yesterday."],
    "answer": "I would reset it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Would you help me with this report ?",
    "options": ["Yes, I would.", "Yes, I will do.", "Yes, I can.", "Yes, I did."],
    "answer": "Yes, I would."
  },
  {
    "question": "_________your hands before touching the circuit.",
    "options": ["Washed", "Wash", "Washing", "To wash"],
    "answer": "Wash"
  },
  {
    "question": "Don’t ________ the button until the light turns green.",
    "options": ["press", "pressed", "presses", "pressing"],
    "answer": "press"
  },
  {
    "question": "Please _________ the file before closing the window.",
    "options": ["saving", "saves", "save", "saved"],
    "answer": "save"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ careful when you open that bottle.",
    "options": ["Is", "Be", "Are", "Being"],
    "answer": "Be"
  },
  {
    "question": "Let’s _________ a short break before the next activity.",
    "options": ["take", "taking", "took", "to take"],
    "answer": "take"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you ________ the project details to the team?",
    "options": ["explain", "explaining", "explained", "explains"],
    "answer": "explain"
  },
  {
    "question": "She can’t _______ the files because the computer is off.",
    "options": ["open", "opens", "opened", "opening"],
    "answer": "open"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can we use this equipment now? Yes, you _______.",
    "options": ["can", "could", "are", "may not"],
    "answer": "can"
  },
  {
    "question": "We ______ never _______ a project like this before.",
    "options": ["did see", "have /seen", "see", "saw"],
    "answer": "have /seen"
  },
  {
    "question": "My supervisor _______ just ______ the production report.",
    "options": ["has/ finished", "have/ finished", "finished", "finish"],
    "answer": "has/ finished"
  },
  {
    "question": "Please ___ the lights when you leave the lab.",
    "options": ["turn on", "turn off", "take out", "set up"],
    "answer": "turn off"
  },
  {
    "question": "The system will ___ if we restart it now.",
    "options": ["go up", "come on", "shut down", "look after"],
    "answer": "shut down"
  },
  {
    "question": "We need to ___ the problem before the meeting.",
    "options": ["figure out", "take over", "run into", "turn up"],
    "answer": "figure out"
  },
  {
    "question": "The technician will ________ the machine to check the motor.",
    "options": ["look for", "take apart", "put on", "give back"],
    "answer": "take apart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Please ___ the report after you finish it.",
    "options": ["turn up", "turn in", "get off", "run away"],
    "answer": "turn in"
  },
  {
    "question": "In business, “HR” stands for:",
    "options": ["Human Relations", "Human Resources", "High Risk", "Hourly Report"],
    "answer": "Human Resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "“Wi-Fi” allows users to:",
    "options": ["Connect without cables", "Work without computers", "Install hard drives", "Clean monitors"],
    "answer": "Connect without cables"
  },
  {
    "question": "“AI” is an abbreviation for:",
    "options": ["Artificial Intelligence", "Automatic Information", "Artificial Internet", "Active Integration"],
    "answer": "Artificial Intelligence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accountant must _________ all expenses before sending the report.",
    "options": ["register", "verify", "connect", "actívate"],
    "answer": "verify"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IT department performs a full system backup every Friday mainly to:",
    "options": ["reduce electricity consumption", "protect data from possible loss or damage", "install new applications automatically", "delete temporary internet files"],
    "answer": "protect data from possible loss or damage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The company decided to ______ new management software.",
    "options": ["install", "design", "produce", "check"],
    "answer": "install"
  },
  {
    "question": "What tool is used to tighten or loosen bolts?",
    "options": ["Screwdriver", "Wrench", "Pliers", "Tester"],
    "answer": "Wrench"
  },
  {
    "question": "The technician is going to replace the old cable. What does he need?",
    "options": ["A document", "A hammer", "A wire cutter", "A keyboard"],
    "answer": "A wire cutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading Question. The IT support department is responsible for maintaining all computer systems in the institution. Every Friday, the technicians perform a complete data ___________ to avoid losing important information.",
    "options": ["information", "configuration", "backup", "copy"],
    "answer": "backup"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which verb is similar to “turn on”?",
    "options": ["Power off", "Connect", "Switch off", "Shut down"],
    "answer": "Connect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operator can’t start the scanner because the system ________.",
    "options": ["updates", "is off", "works", "record"],
    "answer": "is off"
  }
]
